Daniel Lagos

1160 Dawnell Dr | San Diego CA 92154 | 910-916-7201 Lagos.D@gmail.com | github.com/danlagos | www.linkedin.com/in/d-lagos/

Machine Learning Engineer:

Machine Learning Engineer backed by 10 years of experience as an officer in the US Army and Manager. Seeking a full-time position where I can apply my analytical and technical skills pertaining to Deep Learning for personal and company growth.

SKILLS:

- Python, Jupyter, Pandas, Numpy, Matlib, Scikit-Learn, GitHub
- SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS Data Miner
- JavaScript, Vue, React, Node, Express, SQL
- Deep learning architectures: CNNs, RNNs, Transformers

- Statistical Model Building & Optimization
- Data Analysis, Data Mining, & Data Auditing
- Feature Engineering and Data VisualizationContinuous and Categorical Data Methods
 - Data Analysis Interpretation & Application

EDUCATION:

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY, 2022-2023, GPA: 4.0

Master of Science in Data Science, Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning

Graduation Date: 04/2023

UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX, 2008 - 2010, GPA: 4.0

Master of Business Administration, Finance (32/36 units)

LA SIERRA UNIVERSITY, 2001 - 2003

B.A. Business Administration, eCommerce

EXPERIENCE:

National University, Master's Candidate in Data Science: Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning, March 2022 to April 2023:

- Currently maintains a GPA of 4.0.
- Principal Component Analysis conducted using 2009 California Health Interview Survey to find 3 factors (out of 536 variables) used to measure if a patient is taking medication to mitigate heart disease, receiving medical treatment for heart disease, and the patient's mental state. https://github.com/danlagos/PCA.
- Case Study using multivariable logistic regression to find the association between suicide attempts and gender among high school student in the United States. https://github.com/danlagos/Case_Study.
- Ordinal Logistic Regression conducted to measure the association between poverty levels and depression after adjusting for physical activity among adults in the state of California. https://github.com/danlagos/Ordinal-Log-Regression
- Technology used: Python, SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS Data Miner, Jupyter, Pandas, Numpy, Matlib, Scikit Learn, GitHub.

MortgageOne, Junior Processor, December 2020 to January 2022:

- Personally processed for branch manager and 5 other Loan Officers.
- Performed application review by thoroughly examining AUS findings, credit report, preliminary title report, appraisals, income and asset documentation prior to forwarding the file to underwriting.
- Prioritize and manage a pipeline of 17 to 25 loans per month while acting as a liaison between loan officer, title, and underwriting to ensure closing within 30 to 35 days in 97% of files.

Vallen Distribution, Logistics Specialist, November 2019 to November 2020:

- Manage and process 28 to 32 invoices per day valued in total of \$1,000/day to \$5,000/day.
- Developed best practices and organization procedures saving the department approximately \$3,000 per year in labor expenses.
- Conduct invoicing record keeping processes and identify invoicing discrepancies and process required corrections.
- Provide weekly reports documenting purchase orders and invoicing for internal accounts.
- Technology used: Microsoft Office Products, Vallen Distribution Control Net, CribMaster, SX.e.

Discrete Chill, *Junior Web Developer*, November 2018 to November 2019:

- Led reformatting initiative that converted web-application from standard hard coded Jquery/HTML/CSS to Vue.JS components.
- Built scalable API using TypeScript and GraphQL to fetch product records in order to assist users in product selection based on customers requirements/symptoms.
- Created, designed, implemented relational database using MySQL Workbench in support of web application.
- Presented a Tech Talk explaining the three forms of Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning: Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning, and Reinforced Learning.
- Implemented Graphical User Interface compliant with Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) to allow users to initiate purchase orders.
- Technology used: JavaScript, React, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, React Materialize, gitHub, MySQL Workbench, AWS Amplify, AWS Cognito, AWS DynamoDB, AWS App Sync.

Movement Mortgage, Branch Manager, November 2016 to October 2018:

- Directly managed 17 loan officers, 4 loan officer assistants and 2 processors for a high volume mortgage broker producing on average \$38MM in mortgage loans per month.
- Developed and implemented sales training programs and best practices improving team sales skills, thereby increasing monthly sales volume by 13%.
- Implemented data-driven solutions identifying waste in over-processing and motion and in order to improve speed of mortgage processing transactions by 17%.
- Standardized best practices for team of loan officer assistant's and loan reducing waiting time and extra-processing thereby streamlining internal procedures.
- Developed referral partner relationships with 12 realtors, and 3 CPA's, to augment purchase volume.

Mortgage Loan Officer, July 2010 to October 2016:

- Self-sourced mortgage loan officer responsible for developing consumer direct marketing campaigns for first-time home buyers, and cash-out refinance clients.
- Designed and implemented CRM, lead capture, and lead generation systems (averaging 45-75 leads per day), to convert leads generated self-created direct mail, social media, and internet marketing campaigns.
- Personally funded an average of 7 loans per month totaling approximately \$2.8MM in funded loans.

US Army, Operations Officer (Operations Officer) - Captain, November 2006 to September 2008:

- Directly led and supervised 4 first line supervisors and 78 civilians/service-members responsible for Medical,
 Testing, and Operations Departments for US Military's largest Recruit Entrance Processing Station.
- Oversaw the processing, contracting, physical examination, and shipping of over 12,000 applicants per year into their respective branches of military service (US Army, US Navy, US Marine Corps, US Coast Guard, US National guard).
- Negotiated all non-traditional business relationships within the Los Angeles Area including physician networks, and hospitality operations.
- Mapped, documented, and redesigned LA MEPS business processes increasing capacity by 63%.

US Army, IT Business Analyst (S6) - Captain, April 2006 to November 2006:

- Led IT department consisting of a staff of 5 Soldiers responsible for all communications, and IT assets for a newly commissioned 600-man Aviation Support Battalion.
- Field tested & deployed Battalion Communication assets including newly fielded Joint Network Node system, Secure Internet Protocol, Non-Secure Internet Protocol, Command Post Network system, Fusion Net, & ASIP radio network.
- Conducted Field testing and deployment of Force XXI Battle Command Brigade and Below, a linux based system allowing commanders to track friendly and hostile forces on the battlefield in real-time.
- Streamlined operations by creating standardized best practices for all IT business processes, improving efficiency by 27%.
- Developed IT training program for 600 Soldiers in preparation for Operation Enduring Freedom V (deployment to Afghanistan).

US Army, General Manager (Platoon Leader) - 1st Lieutenant, April 2004 to March 2006:

- Tactical communications platoon leader providing worldwide support to XVIII Airborne Corps Headquarters.
- Directly led and supervised 4 subordinate first line supervisors, and a total of 76 Soldiers, and was responsible for 15 tactical vehicles, 5 communications assemblages, and other auxiliary equipment valued over \$8MM.
- Set up NIPR and SIPR net, deployed VOIP network, and maintained LAN in Iraq LSA Anaconda.
- Provided switching systems and a TIER 2 data trunk as part of strategic communications infrastructure for corp headquarters.
- Streamlined business processes to achieve operational readiness of 97%, 7% above battalion standard.